[Episode 28]
Father, I have long fallen for Zhi Li.
Zhi Li is like a precious treasure
in my heart.
I cannot watch people judge her at all.
I established my own household
because I want to give her the best.
I know
it's still not enough to prove my sincerity.
So I accept any test you set for me.
Nian,
I watched you grow up.
You have always had courage and principles.
Although you are young,
you have always been steady
in speech and action.
But this time,
I won't arrange Zhi Li's marriage.
Zhi Li chooses her own husband.
Zhi Li,
will you marry me?
With the Shen family weakened,
how could I possibly rush into marriage?
Rest assured. As long as I am here,
I won't let anyone
slight the Shen family again.
I can ask His Majesty to decree our marriage
so you can marry into the Di family
with honor and glory.
Do you really not care at all
about what happened to me?
I don't care at all.
But do you know
the knot in my heart can't be undone
by a simple 'I don't care'?
Even if I marry you,
I will not love you.
I will never force your feelings.
I know my proposal today is abrupt,
but I also did it to protect
the Shen family's reputation.
I have no intention
of taking advantage of you.
If one day your heart belongs to another,
I will never stand in your way.
Trust me.
I will never let you suffer
any grievance or harm.
Not ever in this lifetime.
Zhi Li, I understand your current worries.
You deserve all the goodness in this world.
Whatever you decide,
your family's integrity will never falter.
Nian,
I trust you.
I am willing to marry you.
[Shen Mansion]
Don't worry.
We'll be here with you for the journey ahead.
My lord, my lady,
everything is ready outside.
- Everything is ready?
- It's ready?
Lin, light the fire.
It's so beautiful.
[Shen Mansion]
So beautiful.
This one looks nice.
Don't worry.
Di Nian can pluck
the stars and moon for Zhi Li
and also give her the freedom to roam beyond.
Perhaps this is also a gift.
By the time of their wedding,
Fu Zhi and Mr. Shen should be back as well.
Now that the Huxiao Gang
and its protective umbrella
have been completely eliminated.
Director Meng, I must congratulate you
on getting what you wished for.
What I wished for
is also what Your Majesty had in mind.
If we are to say congratulations,
it should be me congratulating Your Majesty.
I remember you once said
that one should make a wish
on the first snow.
You have achieved another great merit.
Tell me what you want.
Your Majesty already knows.
My wish has always been
to stand in the court and serve.
Is there no wish concerning me?
To walk side by side
and light each other's way for a while
is to live without regret.
I would not make it hard for Your Majesty,
nor would I be greedy.
Then I shall be greedy on your behalf.
I want you to have
both power and a true heart.
The dragon and phoenix pendants
accompanied my parents for over thirty years.
The dragon is the emperor,
and the phoenix the empress.
Today, with the snow
on the West Mountain as my witness,
I entrust this one to you.
I know what you want
is not the position of empress.
Even less to be trapped in the inner palace.
But this is my promise to you.
I deeply trust Your Majesty.
But the ancestral precepts forbid it.
I would rather be a blade
and a voice of truth
so that Your Majesty
can enjoy the glory of the world.
Ancestral precepts are dead,
but people are alive.
I am reforming officialdom and the court
because I refuse to bend to tradition.
A position of power, I give you.
A life without regret, I'll live it with you.
These two things
have never been mutually exclusive.
I am willing to share
the weight of this realm with you.
I am willing to accompany Your Majesty
to secure the realm,
nurture the people,
and achieve lasting peace.
[Happiness]
First bow to Heaven and Earth.
Second bow to the parents.
Third bow to each other.
Perform the nuptial cup ceremony.
Drink the nuptial wine together.
May the couple live together until old age.
Congratulations.
Wonderful.
My lady, the Marquis
has dismissed the guests.
He said you are tired today
and should rest in the inner chamber.
He'll sleep on the couch in the outer room
and will not disturb you.
Zhi Li,
you're still awake so late?
Is there something?
Now that we are married,
if we sleep in separate rooms,
what will the court officials say
if word of this gets out?
I'd like to see who dares call this a sham.
Rest assured.
With me here, no one will dare to bully you.
From now on, let's just be like
we were at the Shen family.
You should go to bed early.
You have preserved
the Shen family's reputation.
I don't want to harm your reputation
because of my faults.
Your authority in the military
must not be diminished in the slightest.
Especially now that you have
inherited the title.
Since I have married you,
I will by no means
be ignorant of these matters.
No matter what,
I will not let you suffer any grievance.
From now on,
you, Di Nian,
are the husband of me, Shen Zhi Li.
And the Di Mansion is my home.
You treat me well,
and I will treat you well in return.
Zhi Li, although we are married,
I will respect you.
I will wait until you truly like me.
You look so beautiful when you smile.
Zhi Li,
you sleep here, and I'll sleep on the couch.
Call me if you need anything in the night.
[Censorate]
Director Meng.
It's windy today. Put this on.
Don't catch a cold.
I can do it myself.
Let me.
There's still much to do. Get back to work.
Don't worry.
I won't neglect a single task
you have entrusted to me.
There.
I'm off.
In the third year of Jingyuan
of the Ning Empire,
the imperial grand sacrifice is held.
May Heaven bless us
and grant favor to all the people.
The sacred ancestors built the realm
and handed down the precepts.
[Ancestral Spirit Tablets]
His Majesty offers the ritual vessels,
bows to the ancestors,
and leads all officials
in the sacred ceremony.
We humbly offer this to the spirits.
Kneel and bow.
Second bow.
Third bow.
Today is the grand ancestral offering.
With the ancestors above,
I personally issue an edict of reform.
The founding emperor set down twelve precepts
at the realm's dawn,
which have lasted through three reigns.
But times have changed.
Three among those twelve:
the ban on ruler-subject love,
the perpetual servitude law,
and the official-nominated empress selection,
are no longer suitable for the times.
Taking official-nominated
empress selection for example,
it was meant to balance
the ruler and the officials
but was nearly exploited by evil hands
and almost brought calamity.
After much deliberation,
any outdated precepts
that hinder the nation's strength
must be completely uprooted.
Your Majesty, since ancestral precepts
were established,
they haven't been altered for three reigns.
For Your Majesty to rashly abolish them,
what does that make of the ancestors
and the palace rules and rites?
There is no construction without destruction.
If we follow every old practice
and cling to rigid rules,
that'd be to defy the ancestors' true intent.
Your Majesty is wise.
The remnants of Zhongwan are lurking.
Reforming now
will only lead to chaos in the court.
- If enemies exploit this and strike...
- Without internal worries,
why fear external threats?
If the court is united as one,
even if surrounded by powerful enemies,
what does our country have to fear?
There is no need for further discussion.
My decision is final.
This is the phoenix pendant
the late emperor gave the late empress.
It's the imperial couple's token.
Your Majesty is not yet married.
How did an official like you
get such an important token?
Audacious Meng Ting Hui!
How dare you covet the position of empress!
During the case
of the true and false Huiyuan,
I suspected you had ill intentions.
You claim to serve the court,
but you're angling for His Majesty's favor
and the empress's place.
Now, thinking back carefully,
she went after the Right Chancellor,
set up the Shen family,
and destroyed Lady Shen's reputation
all to pave her own way
to become empress, didn't she?
Those words are far too biased.
If not for Director Meng,
would Ling Yun Fei, the Huxiao Gang,
or even the treacherous Gu Qin
hiding in the court
have been brought to justice so quickly?
Stop changing the subject.
Why is the phoenix pendant in her hands?
I gave it to her.
I personally gave the phoenix pendant
to Meng Ting Hui.
A love between ruler and subject
is a forbidden crime.
Does Your Majesty mean--
That's right.
I love Meng Ting Hui.
I have decided
to abolish the ban on ruler-subject love.
Of the three outdated precepts
Your Majesty said to abolish,
I'm afraid you only want to abolish this one
to elevate Meng Ting Hui
to the position of empress.
An evil woman that beguiles the ruler
deserves death by a thousand cuts
by ancestral precepts.
Not one of the 360 articles
of the Ning Empire's law includes this crime.
Your Majesty!
For the so-called ancestral precepts,
if they are outdated,
they should be reformed.
If Your Majesty breaks
one precept for her today,
tomorrow you could abolish
a hundred laws for her.
If this continues, I'm afraid this court
will become the autocracy
of Your Majesty and Meng Ting Hui.
What need would there be
for officials like us?
What wrong is there in my desire to reform?
I am doing all this
not just for Meng Ting Hui alone.
It is simply that her existence
has made my resolve to reform even more firm
and my pace even faster.
Even if Your Majesty has a thousand reasons,
in the eyes of the world,
you are merely beguiled by this evil woman.
Does Your Majesty not fear
losing the people's hearts
and bearing the infamy of a fatuous ruler?
It's my realm.
I will shoulder it myself.
[Edict of Self-Reproach]
I have issued an Edict of Self-Reproach.
I will proclaim to the world
that the merits and faults of my reform
will be left for later generations to judge.
An Edict of Self-Reproach?
Your Majesty,
Meng Ting Hui holds the great power
of oversight as a woman.
It's already forbidden
by the ancestral precepts.
Now, she and Your Majesty...
It's an omen of national disaster!
The late emperor bestowed
this dragon-head cane upon me
to strike fatuous rulers
and treacherous officials.
In the presence of the ancestors,
I will properly discipline Your Majesty
on behalf of the late emperor!
A calamity star has descended,
wreaking havoc upon the court.
Today, I will rectify the court
and purge the ruler's side!
Lord Xu!
Lord Xu,
I tolerate this strike from you
because you are a veteran of three reigns.
Late emperor,
I have failed to complete
the task you entrusted to me.
But please rest assured.
Even if I must die,
I will not let His Majesty
continue making mistakes
and bear the infamy of a fatuous ruler.
Lord Xu!
Summon the imperial physician!
Wait.
Your Majesty, unless you repeal
the Edict of Self-Reproach
and execute the evil woman,
I would rather die here in this hall.
Lord Xu, you cannot die.
If anyone should die, it should be me.
It is I who has failed the ancestors.
Your Majesty, the foundation
of the Ning Empire was hard-won.
Please listen to Lord Xu
and withdraw the Edict of Self-Reproach.
We beg Your Majesty
to withdraw the Edict of Self-Reproach.
to withdraw the Edict of Self-Reproach
and execute Meng Ting Hui.
We beg Your Majesty
to withdraw the Edict of Self-Reproach
and execute Meng Ting Hui.
Your Majesty,
I acknowledge my crime.
I request to be imprisoned
and await my punishment.
Meng Ting Hui.
I have no regrets.
But if Your Majesty drives a veteran
of three reigns to death because of me,
not even my death could atone for it.
I hope Your Majesty
will prioritize the realm.
Miss Meng, this is a medicine
for feigning death.
After taking it, within twenty-four hours,
your breath and pulse will completely vanish,
and even the imperial physicians
can't find out.
What are you doing?
Saving you and getting you out.
I will not leave.
The officials were enraged in the court.
That's why I requested imprisonment.
And the gold chain's break was strange.
You were just momentarily beguiled,
and your mind was clouded.
All I could do was use the soft gold fuse
to give you a push.
In two hours, the ancestral incense
will be burned,
which is the perfect time
for the gold chain to break.
Do you regret it?
Do you truly believe
he will defy the world for you?
His Majesty is not doing it just for me.
He wants to abolish
the ban on ruler-subject love
and cleave through the Ning Empire's
outdated precepts.
This path is difficult.
But we can't give up
simply because it's difficult.
Your Majesty, these three ancestral precepts
were decreed by the ancestor
and cannot be violated.
His Majesty has great foresight
and is willing to create a precedent.
As his subjects,
we should respectfully comply.
Look at the fine students
Grand Tutor Shen has taught,
each one relying on your backing,
treating the ancestral laws as child's play
and indulging His Majesty's mischief.
Lord Xu,
rites change with the times,
and laws shift with the world.
Breaking the old and establishing the new
is the general trend.
It requires a bold emperor,
daring to be the first under heaven.
Though we are old ministers,
we must never be ones
who cling to the old ways.
What the Grand Tutor says
is absolutely right.
The words His Majesty spoke that day
were enlightening to us,
and today, hearing the Grand Tutor's words
further clears the clouds for us juniors
and inspires us greatly.
Indeed, we are willing to support His Majesty
to break the old and build the new.
Don't you think that in the three years
of His Majesty's rule,
the court has been vibrant
and Ning Empire has taken on
a completely new look?
His Majesty arrives.
Bring forth the Founding Emperor's Whip.
Your Majesty,
the Founding Emperor's Whip is here.
We need someone to execute it.
Lord Xu.
Grand Tutor Shen.
The ancestral precepts are important.
But Your Majesty is the supreme ruler,
and your body concerns the state.
How can it be harmed in the slightest?
Chief Steward You, you do it.
I dare not either.
I'm willing to take the seven lashes
on behalf of Your Majesty.
Chief Steward You,
you know how hard I've fought to get here.
Help me this once.
That lash does not count. Do it again.
Your Majesty.
Chief Steward You, you know how to do it.
The first lash draws blood.
The second lash breaks the flesh.
The third lash shakes the bones.
I deserve ten thousand deaths.
The first lash
strikes me for defying the ancestors' will
and abolishing three ancestral precepts:
the ban on ruler-subject love,
the perpetual servitude law,
and the official-nominated empress selection.
The second lash
strikes me for defying the will of the court
and proclaiming my intent for reform.
Your Majesty!
Imperial Physician Li, quickly!
The third lash
strikes me, the ruler of this realm,
for issuing an Edict of Self-Reproach
and subjecting my body
to the pain of flogging
to apologize to the people
of the Ning Empire.
Continue.
Your Majesty!
My decision is final.
I'll also proclaim to all the officials
that no matter how profound
their past seniority
or how illustrious their merits,
and whether it be palace rules,
ancestral precepts,
or old state customs,
the stability of the Ning Empire comes first.
No one shall ever again
sway my decisions with personal gain.
From this day forward,
the ban on ruler-subject love,
the perpetual servitude law,
and the official-nominated empress selection
shall be forever banished
from Ning's ancestral precepts.
It is time to let the morning sun
shine on the new snow in front of the hall.
So, it turns out it's not the court
that cannot be without me.
Long live the emperor!
You knelt in the snow
for a day and a night for His Majesty.
You truly went all out.
What if the cold causes
lasting damage to your legs?
What His Majesty endured
was a thousand times heavier than mine.
He shouldn't be a ruler wrongfully judged.
He should be a brilliant ruler
in the annals of history.
With such deep affection between you two,
I believe nothing can separate you now.
By the way, Fu Zhi still hasn't written back.
I wonder if her father and stepmother
are making things difficult for her.
Don't worry. With my brother there,
Miss Yan won't be wronged.
I never imagined
a carefree young master like him
would settle down for one person.
His Majesty is the same.
Even if it means defying the whole world,
he still wants to be with you.
It's quite enviable.
Are things going well between you and Nian?
We have lived together since childhood.
Now it's just the same as it always was.
Do you have even a trace
of affection for him now?
If you believe he's a good man,
why not give each other a chance?
He is so good.
I always feel that I've held him back.
Meng, tell me,
why did I agree to this marriage
in the first place?
When a person is in extreme pain,
they always need to find support.
And Nian is the lamp
that guides you forward in the fog.
Because you understand each other,
and he can give you
the peace of mind you need.
But I do care about him.
I can't stand to see him hurt.
I can bear to see him sad
because of me even less.
You don't need to feel guilty.
I just hope you can slowly
let down your guard.
Nian is worth it.
Zhi Li, Director Meng.
Why are you here?
The patrol is over.
I saw you hadn't returned yet
and was worried about you.
Zhi Li,
go home quickly.
I bought the last steamer
of crab roe buns from West Street.
They'll get cold if we don't go back soon.
Also, for the gift list
for tomorrow's return visit,
I added a few bolts of cloud brocade
according to Father and Mother's taste.
See if it's thorough enough.
It's so cold.
You shouldn't have come all this way.
It's precisely because it's so cold
that I should come.
I'll be going now.